AHRAR BASHAR

14 Whitmorr Ct, Noble Park, Victoria · Mobile Number: +61 432 170 654

Email: ahrar.bashar96@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahrar-bashar-1280b4102/

Career Profile

A Monash University graduate majoring in Finance and Economics with an excellent work ethic and an ability to learn and adapt to changing environments. Solid finance knowledge with administrative experience, well developed organizational skills, technological proficiency in BASH, Python, HTML, and JavaScript amongst others. Excellence in customer service, teamwork and adhering to deadlines. All these skills and qualities have been built upon in my self-development and professional experiences.

Education & Professional Development

2021 TO DATE

Full Stack Development, Monash University

Currently undertaking a full stack development course through Monash.

2020-2021

Cloud Computing, MONASH UNIVERSITY

Completed the AWS and Azure Cloud Computing certifications at Tier 1.

2018

RG146-Tier 1 Generic Knowledge, KAPLAN INSTITUTE

2014-2017

Bachelor of Commerce, Monash University, Clayton CAMPUS

Majored in Finance and Economics.

2016

Income Tax Course, H&R BLOCK

Certified in preparing tax returns and using the Reckon Elite software and MYOB.

2013

Completed Year 12, NOSSAL HIGH SCHOOL

Nossal High School is one of the four academic selective schools within Victoria.

Employment History

APR 2018- JUN 2019

Research Assistant, DEAKIN UNIVERSITY

- Used PANDAS and problem-solving skills to sift through datasets.
- Contributed to the automation and development of utilities using Python and BASH.
- Used MS Excel to collate and identify research themes in the data.

JAN 2017 - DEC 2017

Administrative Assistant/Paraplanner, AUSIA HOME LOANS

- Responded to client inquiries and managed appointments.
- Updated client records.
- Analyzed financial statements.

• Calculated mortgage and interest repayments.

FEB 2014 - NOV 2016

Supermarket Sales Assistant, Fresh Warehouse Direct – Seaford

- Maintained and ensured signage and pricing on each product.
- Managed stock in shelves, displays and backup and checked product codes for display order, rotated, and removed out-of-date products.
- Delivered unconditionally high-quality customer service.
- Adhered to safety and cleanliness standards of the store.

Skills

- Advanced Excel Skills (VLOOKUP, Index & Match, Pivot tables, VBA)
- GIT, VMware, SSH, SyncThing, NextCloud, MS Azure Cloud
- Experienced in SQL (PostgreSQL)
- Experienced with JavaScript, HTML and CSS

- Experienced with Python 3 and Anaconda 3
- Experienced with Server Solutions
- Experienced with C, Lua, Bash, Zshell & Perl
- Experienced with Windows and Linux (Debian)
 Environments

Volunteer Experience

2016 - 2017

Volunteer English Tutor, AMES AUSTRALIA

Involved in the teaching of English to recent immigrants and refugees as well as the organization and administration of lessons.

DEC 2015 - JAN 2016

Internship, Grameen Bank, Bangladesh

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Met clientele and observed the micro-transaction program in addition to the social businesses conducted by the bank.
- Collation of data and preparation of reports that entailed the banking activities conducted in two villages consisting of hundreds of clients.
- Involved in the deliberation process of social business ventures to be undertaken by the bank.

2014 - 2015

Volunteer Research Assistant, DEAKIN UNIVERSITY

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Collated and collected data to be used by the Faculty of Management.
- Digitized physical data to be used for computer analysis.

References

Available upon request